Marko Schafer marko.h.schafer@gmail.com 586-339-4551

Professional Profile

Driven data engineer with 4+ years experience wrangling big datasets. Eager to build robust databases that lay the groundwork for revealing game-changing insights at LionHeart Algorithm LLC. Implemented natural language processing tools to make machine-readable databases ready for the team of data scientists. Developed a data pipeline using Delta Lake that led to a client revenue increase of 19%.

Professional Experience

Data Engineer Akira Analytics, New York, NY November 2017–Present

- Translate business propositions into quantitative queries and collect/clean the necessary data.
- Build scalable databases capable of ETL processes using SQL and Spark.
- Evaluate the workflow and increase the efficiency of data pipelines that process over 50 TB of data daily.
- Utilize MongoDB to create NoSQL databases that harvests data from a variety of sources.

Key Achievement: Developed a data pipeline using Delta Lake that led to a process optimization and corresponding revenue increase of 19%.

Junior Data Engineer Big Data Concepts Inc., New York, NY July 2016–October 2017

- Co-developed the SQL server database system to maximize performance benefits for clients.
- Assisted senior level data scientists in the design of ETL processes, including SSIS packages.
- Created coherent Logical Data Models that helped guide important client business decisions

Key Achievement: Solved an ETL issue while following PL/SQL best practices that resulted in an insight that increased client's customer base by 33%.

Education

2012–2016 BS, Computer Science University of Texas at Austin

- Dual concentration in Big Data and Machine Learning
- Received a Business Foundations Certificate
- Part of the winning team for the 2016 Longhorn Hackathon

Skills

- Skilled in Data Architecture, ETL, and Machine Learning
- Extensive experience with Hadoop-based analytics (MapReduce andHive)
- Exposed to NoSQL technologies like MongoDB

Activities

• Volunteer at Data for Good (2019-Present)